Miguanda Tigner

Toronto, ON, Canada migtig1222@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/miguanda-tigner-300922287/

Seasoned Backend Developer with 8 years of experience in software engineering. Always delivering top-tier code and optimizing performance. Specializes in architecting microservices and embraces Test-Driven Development and Behavior-Driven Development using Node.js, Java Spring. Currently seeking a new and exciting opportunity to grow up myself. **Key achievement**: Spearheaded design of the CRM project, which increased performance by 40% in less than 30 days on the job.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Next Level Media, Inc

Senior Full Stack Developer

New York, NY, USA

Aug 2021 - Now

- Managed the development of SaaS product and led a team of 12 members, delivering high quality code with full testing including unit testing, integration testing, and E2E testing.
- Designed and implemented a serverless architecture using AWS Lamda and AWS Fargate, resulting in improved scalability and reduced operational costs by 15%.
- Built several microservices using Node.is, Typescript, Express.is, providing efficient and reliable solutions to complex business problems.
- Enhanced the database performance by using proper indexing and database sharding in PostgreSQL, resulting in improved application performance and reduced database latency by 23%.
- Improved the page loading speed and SEO by introducing new caching architecture and SSR framework like Next, resulting in increased user engagement and better search engine rankings.
- Helped the HR team to hire and mentor 3 junior developers, ensuring the team's growth and development

Portland Webworks. Portland, ME, USA

Backend and Blockchain Developer

Feb 2020-Aug 2021

- Investigated and designed the Layer 2 architecture for a high-performance NFT marketplace, resulting in a scalable and efficient system.
- Developed the core backend service and several microservices using Node.js, NestJS, Typescript, providing reliable and secure functionality for the marketplace.
- Worked closely with the DevOps team to set up and manage the backend services on GCP.
- Wrote test cases that provided more than 80% code coverage, ensuring the quality and stability of the system.
- Wrote smart contracts for the company tokens and the NFT marketplace using Solidity and deployed them using RedHat and Truffle

WeMine Inc. Toronto, Canada Feb 2015-Jan 2020

Junior Software Engineer

- Branded, designed, developed, and implemented several web interfaces, graphics & layouts.
- Entered content and updated an average of 5 HTML newsletters per week.
- Developed and maintained Java-based web applications including implementing new features and fixing bugs.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality software within tight deadlines.

EDUCATION

Ryerson University

Master of Computer Science,

York, Canada May 2014

SKILLS

- JavaScript, Typescript
- Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js
- Java, Java Spring, Java EE
- Python, Rust
- React.js, Angular.js, React Native,
- PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB
- Redis, Kafka, RabbitMQ
- REST APIs, GraphQL
- Jest, Cypress, SuperTest
- TDD, DDD, BDD architecture
- AWS, GCP
- Serverless, Microfrontend, Microservice
- Docker, Kubernete, CI/CD
- GitHub, GitLab, Bit Bucket
- SAAS, Blockchain